https://www.optuma.com/privacy-policy/

Updated July 1st 2019
Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. Because we gather certain types of information about the users of Optuma products and services, we feel you should fully understand the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. This privacy statement discloses what information we gather, how we use it, and how to correct or change it.
Please note that Optuma Pty Ltd is an Australian registered company. In this document when we say “Optuma”, “We” or “us”, we are referring to the company. Our policy covers us and any subsidiaries who operate around the world on our behalf.
If you do not agree with this policy, do not access or use our Products and Services or interact with any other aspect of our business.
Below you will find the following information on our Privacy Policy:
What information this site gathers/tracks about you
What this site does with the information it gathers/tracks
With whom this site shares the information it gathers/tracks
This site’s policy on correcting and updating personally identifiable information
This site’s policy on deleting or deactivating your information from its database
How we protect your credit card account information.
Questions regarding this statement should be directed to the Optuma Client Services Department for clarification. To return to the page you came from, please use the Back button on your browser.
1. Information Optuma Gathers and Tracks
Optuma gathers two types of information about users: data that users provide through downloads; and data Optuma gathers through aggregating tracking information derived mainly by tallying page views throughout our sites and click-throughs from any of our partners. Such information enables us to better tailor our content to readers’ needs and to help our partners better understand the demographics of our audience. Because Optuma may in the future derive revenue from advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential. Optuma does not, and will not, divulge information about an individual user to a third party at any time.
Optuma gathers user information in the following processes:
Download Forms
During the download process the user is required to supply their name, contact phone number and email address, and may also be required to answer mandatory survey questions about age, gender, income, Internet connection, zip code, country, employment status, and other employment information.
Polling
Occasionally Optuma will conduct offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what the Optuma audience thinks about important issues. Optuma uses a system to “tag” users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.
Electronic Newsletters (Dispatches)
Optuma delivers newsletters, marketing and product offerings via email to people who have requested to be added to our Mailing list and people who purchased or trialed Market Analyst & Optuma products. The email tracking system recognizes the URL that was clicked, and records some information about you and your computer, such as the email address that you provided to us, the browser, operating system and IP address.
Optuma also uses the feature of your browser to set a “cookie” on your system. This allows us to measure and report the click through rate on e-mails delivered and then better determine future content.
While aggregate counts of click through behavior are provided to advertisers, an advertiser will never know that a specific user clicked their ad. Optuma will not provide specific user information to any third party company.
Surveys
Occasionally Optuma conducts user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.
Usage Tracking
Optuma tracks user traffic patterns throughout our site.
Optuma sometimes tracks and catalogs the search terms that users enter in our Site Search, but this tracking is never associated with individual users.
Cookies
A cookie is a small data file that certain Web sites write to your hard drive when you visit them. A cookie file can contain information such as a user ID that the site uses to track the pages you’ve visited. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself. A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Optuma uses cookies to track user traffic patterns (as described above);
If you’ve set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie.
You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser.
You do not need to have cookies turned on to use the Optuma sites. However, you the cookie will assist you by filling in information on our site that you have entered previously.
2. Use of the Information
Optuma uses any information voluntarily given by our users to enhance the experience of our site, whether to provide interactive or personalized elements on the sites or to better prepare future content based on the interests of our users.
As stated above, Optuma uses information that users voluntarily provide in order to send out electronic newsletters. We send out newsletters to subscribers on a regular schedule (depending on the newsletter), and occasionally send out special editions when we think subscribers might be particularly interested in something we are doing. Optuma never shares newsletter mailing lists with any third parties, including advertisers or partners.
When we use tracking information to determine which areas of our sites users like and don’t like based on traffic to those areas. Optuma does not track what individual users read, but rather how well each page performs overall. This helps us continue to build a better service for you.
We track search terms entered in our site search as one of many measures of what interests our users. But we don’t track which terms a particular user enters.
Optuma creates aggregate reports on user demographics and traffic patterns for advertisers and partners. This allows our advertisers to advertise more effectively, and allows our users to receive advertisements that are pertinent to their needs.
Security of the Information
Any information about you which you provided, or was derived from your use of Optuma products and services, is stored on servers that are controlled by Optuma. At this time, there are no third parties that have access to your information except our merchant providers (see Credit Card Security below). This means that all your information is controlled by us on our secure servers.
All Optuma servers are updated on a regular basis and are under constant review and monitoring. Optuma uses many techniques to ensure that your information is safe and your Optuma services run without interruption.
3. Sharing of the Information
Optuma uses the above-described information to tailor our content to suit your needs and assist our advertisers to better understand our audience’s demographics. We do not share information about individual users with any third party.
Optuma does not control the practices of our advertisers. If you have questions about how one of our advertisers uses information about you when you click their ad and go to their content, please contact them directly. (Optuma will divulge information only as necessary to comply with state and federal laws.)
Sharing with Third Parties
Currently all aspects of the Optuma businesses are controlled and operated by Optuma. Your personal information is not required to be shared with any third party for us to provide our services to you. We do reserve the right however to partner with a third party firm if we believe that doing so would enable us to provide a better service to our clients. In that instance, the third party may require that we share information about you so that they can provide services on our behalf. Any third party that has access to information about you will do so under instruction from us, including abiding by policies and procedures designed to protect your information.
Sharing with Partners
We work with many partners who have provided technological information that enable us to offer custom tools/services/modules to our clients. If you add on a custom tool/service/module to your Optuma products, your name, email & phone number will be shared with the provider of that tool/service/module to enable them to be able to support you.
Sharing with Affiliated Companies
We share information we collect with affiliated companies and, in some cases, with prospective affiliates. Affiliated companies are companies majority owned or operated by Optuma. The protections of this privacy policy apply to the information we share in these circumstances.
Optuma Companies: We share information we have about you with Optuma corporate affiliates in order to operate and improve products and services and to offer other Optuma affiliated services to you. This includes companies that own or operate the services in the Optuma product family.
Business transfers: We may share or transfer information we collect under this privacy policy in connection with any merger, sale of company assets, financing, or acquisition of all or a portion of the Optuma businesses to another company. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on the Services if a transaction takes place, as well as any choices you may have regarding your information.
4. Correct/Update Policy
Optuma offers users the ability to correct or change the information collected during registration for any site (see above). This is done by logging into the Optuma self-service portal at portal.optuma.com/myaccount or by contacting the Optuma  Client Services Department
5. Delete/Deactivate Policy
Users may unsubscribe to any of our electronic newsletters at any time by following the instructions contained at the end of every newsletter.
If a user wishes for all their personal information to be completely deleted from all of our servers, they can do this by logging into the Optuma self-service portal by logging into https://portal.optuma.com/myaccount and select “Delete Account”. Note that this is unreversable. A user can also request our staff delete all their information by contacting our Client Services Department
What happens when your data is deleted.
If you have no invoices for any of our services, and you have not trialed one of our products/services for 6 months, all your personal data will be deleted from all our databases. Note: this can take up to 24 hours to propagate to all our servers.
If you have paid an invoice for one of our products/services, then we need to keep the invoices on file for our accounting obligations. In this instance your name will be reduced to your initials only and all your other contact information will be deleted.
If you have recently trialed one of our products/services, then your contact information will be deleted but your record maintained for six months to prevent new trials from being established.
When does Optuma Delete Data
On an annual basis we review data on our servers to ensure that any personal data that is no longer required is deleted. Typically a user meets this qualification when they unsubscribe from all our newsletters and they have no invoice history.
6. Credit Card Security
At Optuma Pty Ltd we take the security of your payment information seriously. We are constantly reviewing our processes to ensure that security is maintained, best practices are followed and we are protecting you from unauthorized access to your private information.
Optuma Pty Ltd does not store client credit cards on any server, log file, database or list. Credit card numbers can only be entered into our system on the secure portal.optuma.com website. Card details are then transmitted via encrypted connections to our merchant providers for processing. For active subscriptions, card details are stored on the merchant’s servers and a token system is used for subsequent billing. All our merchants are fully PCI class 1 complaint and meet all the requirements for the secure storage of credit card details.
All Optuma Pty Ltd servers are maintained by our own staff. No third party has any access to our servers. Servers are constantly updated to ensure that all known security vulnerabilities are patched.
Black Friday Specials Starting Soon
You’re Too Early
Black Friday
Is Coming
Optuma Trial Form 2018
Blocked Country
Region Not Supported
Thank you for your interest in Optuma.
Unfortunately at this time support for Optuma is not available in your region.
There are many reasons support for Optuma may not be available in your region. This includes issues with tax-collection, limits with financial transactions, export fees and even laws against exporting of software technology.
We are constantly working on expanding our reach into new areas around the globe, and if you would like to be contacted if/when we are able to provide a trial to your region, please enter your name and email address details below.
Name
*
Email
*
Unsupported Country
*
Select Value
AUSTRALIA
COTE D'IVOIRE
CROATIA (local name: Hrvatska)
CUBA
CYPRUS
CZECH REPUBLIC
DENMARK
DJIBOUTI
DOMINICA
DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
EAST TIMOR
ETHIOPIA
FALKLAND ISLANDS (MALVINAS)
FAROE ISLANDS
FIJI
FINLAND
FRANCE
FRANCE, METROPOLITAN
FRENCH GUIANA
FRENCH POLYNESIA
FRENCH SOUTHERN TERRITORIES
HEARD AND MC DONALD ISLANDS
HOLY SEE (VATICAN CITY STATE)
HONDURAS
HONG KONG
HUNGARY
ICELAND
INDIA
INDONESIA
IRAN (ISLAMIC REPUBLIC OF)
IRAQ
IRELAND
ISRAEL
ITALY
JAMAICA
JAPAN
JORDAN
KAZAKHSTAN
SINGAPORE
SLOVAKIA (Slovak Republic)
SLOVENIA
SOLOMON ISLANDS
SOMALIA
SOUTH AFRICA
SOUTH GEORGIA AND THE SOUTH SANDWICH ISLANDS
SPAIN
SRI LANKA
ST. HELENA
VIET NAM
VIRGIN ISLANDS (BRITISH)
VIRGIN ISLANDS (U.S.)
WALLIS AND FUTUNA ISLANDS
WESTERN SAHARA
YEMEN
YUGOSLAVIA
ZAMBIA
ZIMBABWE
Your Details
First Name
COTE D'IVOIRE
CROATIA (local name: Hrvatska)
CUBA
CYPRUS
CZECH REPUBLIC
DENMARK
DJIBOUTI
DOMINICA
DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
EAST TIMOR
ETHIOPIA
FALKLAND ISLANDS (MALVINAS)
FAROE ISLANDS
FIJI
FINLAND
FRANCE
FRANCE, METROPOLITAN
FRENCH GUIANA
FRENCH POLYNESIA
FRENCH SOUTHERN TERRITORIES
HEARD AND MC DONALD ISLANDS
HOLY SEE (VATICAN CITY STATE)
HONDURAS
HONG KONG
HUNGARY
ICELAND
INDIA
INDONESIA
IRAN
IRAQ
SINGAPORE
SLOVAKIA (Slovak Republic)
SLOVENIA
SOLOMON ISLANDS
SOMALIA
SOUTH AFRICA
SOUTH GEORGIA AND THE SOUTH SANDWICH ISLANDS
SPAIN
SRI LANKA
ST. HELENA
VIET NAM
VIRGIN ISLANDS (BRITISH)
VIRGIN ISLANDS (U.S.)
WALLIS AND FUTUNA ISLANDS
WESTERN SAHARA
YEMEN
YUGOSLAVIA
ZAMBIA
ZIMBABWE
Your Details
Fill in the information below for your instant trial
COTE D'IVOIRE
CROATIA (local name: Hrvatska)
CUBA
CYPRUS
CZECH REPUBLIC
DENMARK
DJIBOUTI
DOMINICA
DOMINICAN REPUBLIC
EAST TIMOR
ETHIOPIA
FALKLAND ISLANDS (MALVINAS)
FAROE ISLANDS
FIJI
FINLAND
FRANCE
FRANCE, METROPOLITAN
FRENCH GUIANA
FRENCH POLYNESIA
FRENCH SOUTHERN TERRITORIES
HEARD AND MC DONALD ISLANDS
HOLY SEE (VATICAN CITY STATE)
HONDURAS
HONG KONG
HUNGARY
ICELAND
INDIA
INDONESIA
IRAN
IRAQ
SINGAPORE
SLOVAKIA (Slovak Republic)
SLOVENIA
SOLOMON ISLANDS
SOMALIA
SOUTH AFRICA
SOUTH GEORGIA AND THE SOUTH SANDWICH ISLANDS
SPAIN
SRI LANKA
ST. HELENA
VIET NAM
VIRGIN ISLANDS (BRITISH)
VIRGIN ISLANDS (U.S.)
WALLIS AND FUTUNA ISLANDS
WESTERN SAHARA
YEMEN
YUGOSLAVIA
ZAMBIA
ZIMBABWE
Credit Card Details
Card Type
<span class="ccv-link ccv-link-close">What is this?</span>
What is this?
The numbers in the red boxes are the CVC numbers needed. AMEX is a 4 digit number on the front of the card. VISA and Master Card are the last 3 digits on the back of the card.
Submit
If you are human, leave this field blank.
Privacy Policy
Our privacy policy prohibits us from selling, renting or giving your private information to any other company or person. You will receive the occasional email from us, however if you decide you do not want to receive them anymore, simply click the unsubscribe link we include at the bottom of our emails and you will be removed from our mailing list.
Why is a Credit Card Required?
While the Optuma trial is free, a credit card is required. A pre-authorisation of $1 is made against the card as a form of identity verification. No further automatic charges are made once the trial expires unless you opt to purchase or subscribe.
×
Pin It on Pinterest
Share This
Facebook
Twitter
LinkedIn
Google+
Like
By continuing to use the site, you agree to the use of cookies. more information AcceptThe cookie settings on this website are set to "allow cookies" to give you the best browsing experience possible. If you continue to use this website without changing your cookie settings or you click "Accept" below then you are consenting to this.Close
